Guide to the Robert L. Patten: George Cruikshank research materials, 1792 - 2002, bulk 1836-1977 MS 493
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series IV: Prints, pamphlets, illustrations, paintings and plates, 1807-1988, 235387; (17 boxes)
  - Sub-series A: Illustrations for books, pamphlets, tracts and periodicals, 1815-1903., 235544
    - The Universal Songster; or Museum of Mirth, 1826, 235551 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - The Universal Songster, 1826, 235550 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Waverly Novels (Sir Walter Scott), 1836-1838, 235549 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Waverly Novels (Sir Walter Scott), 1836-1838, 235548 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Whom to Marry (Mayhew Brothers), 1848, 235547 (Box 72)
    - The World's Show, 1851, 235546 (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - 2 albums with illustrations, mounted and loose plates, circa 1854-1875, 235545
  - Sub-series B: Individual prints, caricatures, lottery puffs, 1821-1871, undated, 235537
    - Business card, Bookseller & Importer, J.M. Bouton, 1871, 235543 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Her Majesty's Theatre (admission tickets), 1848, 235542 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Meaness - Mrs. Pry and Rapture - Sir William Courteous (lottery puff), 235541 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - The Mother Red-cap Public House, in Opposition to the King's Head, 1821 April 25, 235540 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Shakespeare Tercentenary, Workman's Memorial Subscription Card, 235539 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Warren's Blacking (advertisement), 235538 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Sub-series C: Works for Charles Dickens, circa 1836-1864, 235513
    - George Cruikshank illustrated two works listed in this sub-series ( Oliver Twist and Sketches by Boz); the first two monthly installments of The Pickwick Papers were illustrated by Robert Seymour, and then, upon Seymour's suicide, by Hablot Knight Browne (pseud. Phiz)., 235536
    - Oliver Twist, Oliver asking for more, Bentley's Miscellany, 1837, 235535 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Oliver Twist, loose plates, 1837-1838, 235534 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Oliver Twist, loose plates, 1837-1838, 235533 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Oliver Twist, Fagin in the Condemned Cell, 1st octavo edition, 1846, 235532 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Our Mutual Friend (illustrations by Marcus Stone), wrapper, [1864], 235531 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Pickwick Papers, illustrations by Robert Seymour, R.W. Buss and "Phiz" (Hablot Knight Browne), 51 plates, 1837, 235530 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Pickwick Papers, illustrated by Robert Seymour and "Phiz" (Hablot Knight Browne), 6 plates, 1837, 235529 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Pickwick Papers, illustrated by Robert Seymour and "Phiz" (Hablot Knight Browne), 7 plates, 1837, 235528 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Pickwick Papers, illustrated by Robert Seymour and "Phiz" (Hablot Knight Browne), 8 plates, 1837, 235527 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Pickwick Papers, illustrated by Robert Seymour and "Phiz" (Hablot Knight Browne), 9 plates, 1837, 235526 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Pickwick Papers, illustrated by Robert Seymour and "Phiz" (Hablot Knight Browne), 13 plates, 1837, 235525 (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Sketches by Boz, 1st series, Vol. I & II, 1836, 235524 (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - Sketches by Boz, 2nd series, 1836, 235523 (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - Sketches by Boz, 2nd series, 1836, 235522 (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - Sketches by Boz, 2nd series, 1836, 235521 (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - Sketches by Boz, loose plates, 1836, 235520 (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - Sketches by Boz, 2nd series, 2nd edition, forged title page, 1837, 235519 (Box 74, Folder 23)
    - Sketches by Boz, 2nd series, 2nd edition, 1837, 235518 (Box 74, Folder 24)
    - Sketches by Boz, "New Complete Edition," incomplete, 1839, 235517 (Box 74, Folder 25)
    - Sketches by Boz, loose plates, no imprint, circa 1836-1839, 235516 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Sketches by Boz, frontispeice proof, 1850, 235515 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Sketches by Boz, Works of Charles Dickens, Library edition, 1861, 235514 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Sub-series D: Works for William Harrison Ainsworth, 1834-1845, 235498
    - Ainsworth, W. H., portrait, Engraved by E. Finden, from a painting by Daniel Maclise R.A., undated, 235512 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Ainsworth's Magazine, 6 pgs., circa 1841, 235511 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Ainsworth's Magazine, wrappers, 1844-45, 235510 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Guy Fawkes, in Bentley's Miscellany, Book 1, Chapter 14 and Book 3, Chapter 5, 1840, 235509 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Guy Fawkes, loose pages and plates, 1841, 235508 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Guy Fawkes, in Bentley's Miscellany Books 1-3, 1841, 235507 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Jack Sheppard, loose pages and plates, 1839, 235506 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - The Miser's Daughter, 15 etchings, 1842, 235505 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Old Saint Paul's, wrapper, woodcut design, 1841, 235504 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Rookwood, 12 etchings, 1834, 235503 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - St. James, or the Court of Queen Anne, 1844, 235502 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - The Tower of London, loose plates, 1840, 235501 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - The Tower of London, loose plates, 1840, 235500 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Windsor Castle, etched frontispiece, loose plates, 1843, 235499 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series E: Isaac, Robert and Percy Cruikshank, circa 1817, 1864, 235495
    - Isaac Cruikshank, circa 1817, 235497 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Robert and Percy Cruikshank, circa 1864, undated, 235496 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Sub-series F: Miscellaneous prints, other printed matter, 1819-1945, undated, 235468
    - This sub-series contains various loose prints (some unidentified), pamphlets, advertisements, testimonials, bookplates, catalogs, notes, and other printed material., 235494
    - Advertisements, circa 1850's, 235493 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Allen's Great Midland Almanac, 1859, 235492 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Bank Restriction Note, [1819], 235491 (Box 76)
    - A Battle of Engravers, undated, 235490 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Biographies and testimonials, 1873, 1878, 1945, undated, 235489 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Book plates (A.M. Cohn), undated, 235488 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Book wrappers and covers, 1871, 1890, undated, 235487 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Catalogs, 1875-1879, 235486 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Catalogs and advertisements, 1937-1928, undated, 235485 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - George Cruikshank, notes and sketches, undated, 235484 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - George Cruikshank, in the Westminster Review (William Thackeray), undated, 235483 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - The Kaleidoscope, 1828 September 2, 235482 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Memorial broadside, 1878, February, 235481 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous prints and fragments, 1846, undated, 235480 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, circa 1854-55, 1882, 235479 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Mr. George Cruikshank's Great Picture, subscription notice and form, circa 1863, 235478 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Pen and ink drawing, suggestion of Oliver Goldsmith, undated, 235477 (Box 77)
    - Popping the question, etching in color, undated, 235476 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Portrait, George Cruikshank, undated, 235475 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Proofs, unidentified, undated, 235474 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Reviews and catalogs, 1861, 1863, undated, 235473 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Single plates and prints, circa 1800's, undated, 235472 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Sir Lionel Flamstead and his Friends, undated, 235471 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - The Works of Charles Lever, reprinted from Blackwoods' Magazine, 1862 April, 235470 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Worship of Bacchus, a critique of the painting, by John Stewart, 1863, 235469 (Box 77, Folder 16)
  - Sub-series G: Reproductions, negatives, 1988, undated, 235457
    - Contact sheets, negatives, 235467 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Good Living series for Prodexin advertisements, illustrations by George and Robert Cruikshank, undated, 235466 (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Photocopies and reproductions, identified prints, 235465 (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Photocopies and reproductions, unidentified prints, 235464 (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Photo reproductions, Tower of London, 235463 (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - Photo reproductions, Tower of London, other works, undated, 235462 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Photo reproductions, miscelleanous prints, 235461 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Photo reproductions, miscelleanous prints, 235460 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Photo reproductions, title pages, 235459 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Wall calendar prints (reproductions), 1988, 235458 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series H: Oversize prints, drawings and other printed material, 1807-1869, 1968, undated, 235388
    - The Bottle, in eight plates, 1847, 235456
    - 'An Affecting Scene in the Downs' in the Autumn of 1809, undated, 235455
    - The Rival Fountains, lithograph, undated, 235454 (Box 79)
    - Our Gutter Children, 2 prints, 1869, 235453 (Box 79)
    - Worship of Bacchus (reproduction), undated, 235452 (Box 79)
    - Portfolio, The Bottle, and The Drunkard's Children, 3 covers, circa 1847-1848, 235451 (Box 79)
    - Ancient Natives of Britain, encamped near Colchester, E. Evans, undated, 235450 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Bell's Life in London, 1828, 235449 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Burford Cottage, 1835, 235448 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Comic Almanack, etching, Probable Effects of Over Female Emigration, or Importing the Fair Sex from the Savage Islands, 1851, 235447 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Cruikshank, Isaac, prints, circa 1807, 235446 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Cruikshankiana, 33 colored illustrations, 1835, 235445 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Every Night Book, woodcut vignette, (not by George Cruikshank, per Douglas, p. 272), 1827, 235444 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Exhibition poster, University of Louisville Libraries, David Borowitz collection, J.B. Speed Art Museum, 1968, 235443 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - George Cruikshank's Magazine, Tobacco Leaves no. 2, 1854, 235442 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Illustrated London News, A Runaway Knock, 1855 February 17 and Cinderella, with text and illustration, 1854, July 29, 235441 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Illustrations, colored, "A Calf's Pluck, A Pull'd Turkey, Collard Pig, and Rusty Bacon," undated, 235440 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Jack Sheppard, 27 etchings, 2 woodcuts and wrapper, 1839, 235439 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Lecture at the Charterhouse on Stephen Gray's Discoveries in Electricity, undated, 235438 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - The Miser's Daughter, dramatization advertisement, 1842, 235437 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - The Moor, the Mine, and the Forest, Descending the Scar, 2 proofs, undated, 235436 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Oliver Twist, dramatization advertisement, circa 1839, 235435 (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - Pic-Nic Papers, 2 sets, 1841, 235434 (Box 80, Folder 17)
    - Pencil drawings, 1848, 235433 (Box 80, Folder 18)
    - Portrait of George Cruikshank, engraved by D.J. Pound, from a portrait by John and Charles Watkins, undated, 235432 (Box 80, Folder 19)
    - Rapin's History of England, 3 engravings, undated, 235431 (Box 80, Folder 20)
    - The Satirist, or Monthly Meteor, Theatrical Faux Pas, 1814, 235430 (Box 80, Folder 21)
    - Scraps and Sketches, 1832, 235429 (Box 80, Folder 22)
    - Song and lyric sheets, Barney Buntline and Billy Bowling, Fairy Songs and Ballads, Tea in the Arbour, Widow Mahoney, Jack Sheppard Quadrilles, Nix My Dolly Palls Fake Away, Russian Nuptials, Dicky Day (not Cruikshank), La Bagatelle, 1830, undated, 235428 (Box 80, Folder 23)
    - Three Courses and a Dessert, 1830, 235427 (Box 80, Folder 24)
    - Witch, oil on panel, undated, 235426 (Box 80, Folder 25)
    - Christmas Stories, 3 etchings, 1823, Cohn 71, 235425 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Comic Annual, 3 woodcuts, title page, 1830, 235424 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Der Freischutz, etching, Six Shall Achieve, undated, 235423 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Descriptive Account of the Panoramic View…of King George's Sound and the Adjacent Country, 1834, Cohn 218, 235422 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Dicken's covers, Sketches by Boz and Oliver Twist, 1837, 235421 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - First proof of George Cruikshank, drawn by H. Pidgeon, etched by George Cruikshank, undated, 235420 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Gentlemen in Black, 5 woodcuts, tailpiece, title page, 1831,Cohn 219, 235419 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - The Kensington Fine Art Association's Engravings and Etchings Picture Album, by George Cruikshank, cover, undated, 235418 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - The Life of Nelson (Robert Southy), 8 woodcuts, 1861, Cohn 765, 235417 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - London Lyrics (Frederick Locker), 1857, 235416 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Memoir of the Late Captain Joseph Huddart, 1821, Cohn 415, 235415 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - More Mornings on Bow Street, proofs, 1827, 235414 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - My Sketchbook, vol. 1, 1834, 235413 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - New Bath Guide, 5 etchings, 1830, Cohn 34, 235412 (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Original Jests (John Harcourt), etched frontispiece, wrapper, title page, 1827, Cohn 383, 235411 (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - Our Own Times, 1846, 235410
    - The Oyster, 1861, 235409 (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - Philosophy in Sport, 23 woodcuts, 1827, Cohn 626, 235408 (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - A Slice of Bread and Butter, 3 woodcuts, 1857, Cohn 207, 235407 (Box 81, Folder 19)
    - Tales of Irish Life, title page, 6 etchings, proofs on India paper, 1824, Cohn 841, 235406 (Box 81, Folder 20)
    - Topsail Sheet Blocks, 3 etched frontispieces, vol. I, II, III, 1838, Cohn 57, 235405 (Box 81, Folder 21)
    - Walker's Full Account of the Arrest of Sir Francis Burdett, 1810, 235404 (Box 81, Folder 22)
    - The Scourge, The Blessings of Paper Money, 2 prints, Quadrupeds, or the Managers Last Kick, and The Pall Mall Apollo, 1811, 1816, 235403 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - The Moor, the Mine, and the Forest, A Boatful of People in a Cave, original watercolor and pencil sketch, undated, 235402 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - An Election Ball, 1835, 235401 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - George Cruikshank's Table Book, proofs, 235400 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Illustrations to Blanchard Jerrold's, Life of George Cruikshank, 235399 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - History of the Irish Rebellion in 1798 (W.H. Maxwell), Loyal Little Drummer, 1845, 235398 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Caricatures, The Advantages of Travel; or a little learning is a dangerous thing, Scotch Cleanliness, The Last Grand Ministerial Expedition, King's Place & Chandos Street in an Uproar, The Funeral Procession of the Rump, The Peddigree of Corporal Violet, Resignation. A Great Moral Virtue, 1809-1827, 235397 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - The Greatest Plague of Life (Mayhew Brothers), Out for an Airing, and Oh Ah! let 'em ring again, [1847], 235396 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Broadsides, 235395 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Omnibus, proofs, 1842, 235394 (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Omnibus, mounted proofs, woodcuts, 1842, 235393 (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Omnibus, mounted proofs, woodcuts, 1842, 235392 (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - The New Union Club, 1819 and Opening of the Great Industrial Exhibition of All Nations, 1851, 235391 (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Temperance placards and broadsheets, The Queen and the Union, broadside, woodcut, undated, Home in Shadow, no. 4, temperance placard, undated, Our Gutter Children, etching on glass, 1869, A Thing that Drinks and Smokes - A Man who Thinks and Acts, no. 1, undated, Our Gutter Children, 4 pgs., etching on glass, 1869, 235390 (Box 82, Folder 14)
    - Oil painting, no title, undated, 235389 (Box 82)
- Series V: Manuscripts, correspondence and other materials by and about George Cruikshank, circa 1811-1976, 234930; (30 boxes)
  - This series contains autographed letters, drawings and sketches, and other manuscript material. The series also contains notes, correspondence, and other research material. This series is arranged by collection., 235386
  - Sub-Series A: Borowitz collection, circa 1792-1891, 235269
    - Sub-sub-series 1: Correspondence, 1836-1877, undated, 235336
      - Individual correspondents, arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Primarily letters to George Cruikshank unless otherwise noted., 235385
      - A'Beckett, Gilbert Abbott, [1849], 235384 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - Auldjo, John, undated, 235383 (Box 83, Folder 2)
      - Banks, George Linneaus, undated, 235382 (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - Banks, Isabella, 1872 December 31, 235381 (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - Barham, Richard Harris, 1840 May 16, undated, 235380 (Box 83, Folder 5)
      - Bates, William, 1876 August 10, 235379 (Box 83, Folder 6)
      - Blanchard, (Samuel) Laman, undated, 235378 (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - Bloomfield, Walter, 1875 December 10 and 17, 235377 (Box 83, Folder 8)
      - Bogue, David, undated, 235376 (Box 83, Folder 9)
      - Brooks, Robert, undated, 235375 (Box 83, Folder 10)
      - Colburn, Henry, 1843, 235374 (Box 83, Folder 11)
      - Cook, James Joseph, 1873 April 8, 235373 (Box 83, Folder 12)
      - Dawson, Edward B., 1860 February, 235372 (Box 83, Folder 13)
      - Fitzgerald, Percy, 1876 April, 235371 (Box 83, Folder 14)
      - Hall, Anna Marie, 1868 December 5 and 1878 January 9, 235370 (Box 83, Folder 15)
      - Hall, Samuel Carter, ? May 24, 235369 (Box 83, Folder 16)
      - Hockley, Julius L, undated, 235368 (Box 83, Folder 17)
      - Hotten, John Camden, 1860 May 8, 235367 (Box 83, Folder 18)
      - Inglis, E., 1837, 235366 (Box 83, Folder 19)
      - Jerdan, William, ? March 19, 235365 (Box 83, Folder 20)
      - Kent, Charles, 1873 July 27, 235364 (Box 83, Folder 21)
      - Leighton, John, 1866, 235363 (Box 83, Folder 22)
      - Locker, Frederick (to Cruikshank and others),1868, 1870, undated, 235362 (Box 83, Folder 23)
      - MacKenzie, Robert Shelton, 1841, 235361 (Box 83, Folder 24)
      - Macree, Moir, 1872 December 27, 235360 (Box 83, Folder 25)
      - Mayhew, Henry, undated, 235359 (Box 83, Folder 26)
      - Morton, W.S., 1862, 235358 (Box 83, Folder 27)
      - Pocock, Crawford J., 1867, 1870, 1873, 235357 (Box 83, Folder 28)
      - Price, Henry, 1850 November 19, 235356 (Box 83, Folder 29)
      - Pulford, George Cruikshank (godson), undated, 235355 (Box 83, Folder 30)
      - Reid, George William (to and from Cruikshank), 1868-1871, 235354 (Box 83, Folder 31)
      - Sheringham, John, 1852 March 26, 235353 (Box 83, Folder 32)
      - Swynfen, Caroline, 1865 December 9, 235352 (Box 83, Folder 33)
      - Tennent, J. Emil, ? June 6, 235351 (Box 83, Folder 34)
      - Tupper, Martin Farquhar, 1855 April 30 and 1871 October 14, 235350 (Box 83, Folder 35)
      - Personal and family correspondence, George and Eliza Cruiskshank, unknown correspondents and letter fragments, 235349
      - To George Cruikshank, A-W, 1856-1874, undated, 235348 (Box 83, Folder 36)
      - From George Cruikshank, 1850, 1867, 1873, undated, 235347 (Box 83, Folder 37-38)
      - From George Cruikshank to Eliza Cruikshank, 1850-1874, undated, 235346 (Box 83, Folder 39)
      - From George Cruikshank to Mary Cruikshank (mother), 1851, undated, 235345 (Box 83, Folder 40)
      - Eliza Cruikshank, personal and family correspondence, 1836-1878, 235344 (Box 83, Folder 41)
      - Cruikshank, George and Eliza, Christmas greetings, 1873-1877, 235343 (Box 83, Folder 42)
      - Letter fragments, unsigned letters and letters with illegible signatures, 1841-1875, undated, 235342 (Box 83, Folder 43-44)
      - Other correspondence, arranged by subject of correspondence, then chronologically, 235341
      - Robert the Bruce monument, circa 1870-1874, 235340 (Box 83, Folder 45)
      - Robert the Bruce monument, 1870-1877, 235339 (Box 84)
      - Temperance movement, circa 1861, 235338 (Box 84)
      - Volunteers (24th Surrey Havelock), 1865-1868, 235337 (Box 84)
    - Sub-sub-series 2: Eliza and George Cruikshank family papers, documents, and photographs, circa 1792 -1891, 235319
      - Baldwyn, Charles, will and testament, 1818 September 19, 235335 (Box 84, Folder 8)
      - Baldwyn family estate, 1855, 235334 (Box 84, Folder 9)
      - Daybooks, account books, pocket diaries, 1832-1881, incomplete, 235333 (Box 84)
      - Cruikshank, Eliza, death and probate, 1890-1891, 235332 (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - Cruikshank, Eliza, diary, 1853, 1854, 235331 (Box 85, Folder 2)
      - Cruikshank, George, biographical sketches, 1858, undated, 235330 (Box 85, Folder 3)
      - Cruikshank, George, original copperplate of calling card, circa 1800's, 235329 (Box 85, Folder 4)
      - Cruikshank, George, death and memorial, 1878-1890, 235328 (Box 85, Folder 5-6)
      - Cruikshank, George, memo book, 1828 - 1833, 235327 (Box 85, Folder 7)
      - Cruikshank, George, notes, tickets, invitations and other epehmera, 1843-1890, undated, 235326 (Box 85)
      - Cruikshank, George, register of birth and baptism, [1792], 235325 (Box 85, Folder 9)
      - Cruikshank's Silver Wedding Anniversary, 1875, 235324 (Box 85, Folder 10)
      - Linstead family estate, 1851, 1861, 235323 (Box 85, Folder 11)
      - Photographs, Eliza Cruikshank, circa 1864, 235322 (Box 85, Folder 12)
      - Photographs, George Cruikshank, circa 1864, 235321 (Box 85, Folder 13)
      - Photographs, unidentified, circa 1860's - 1870's, 235320 (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - Sub-sub-series 3: Business records, 1833-1888, 235302; no content
      - Accounts and receipts, 1862 -1872, undated, 235318 (Box 85, Folder 15-16)
      - Bell and Daldy, later George Bell and Sons, 1868-1877, 235317 (Box 85, Folder 17)
      - Blackwood, Robert, 1838 March 3, 235316 (Box 85, Folder 18)
      - Booklet listing, India proofs of George Cruikshank presented to Charles Howell, undated, 235315 (Box 85, Folder 19)
      - Booklet, listing of caricatures and plates with dates, published from 1809-1834, undated, 235314 (Box 85, Folder 20)
      - Business correspondence, record, and accounts, 1833-1875, undated, 235313; Includes a printed application for copyright completed by Cruikshank and his wife and signed by him for The Drunkard's Children (Box 85, Folder 21-23)
      - Business records and accounts with George Routledge, 1865-1868, 235312 (Box 85, Folder 24)
      - Donations of George Cruikshank materials, 1884-1888, 235311; Includes notes, receipts, correspondence to the Britsh Museum and others regarding materials donated by Mrs. Cruikshank. (Box 85, Folder 25)
      - Hamilton, Walter, plates wanted, undated, 235310 (Box 85, Folder 26)
      - Notes, lists, accounts, circa 1840-1880, 235309 (Box 85, Folder 27)
      - Over-size business records, 235308
      - Business records and accounts with Charles Tilt, 1833-1839, 235307 (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - Business records and accounts with Richard Bentley, 1840-1848, 235306 (Box 86, Folder 2)
      - Business records and accounts with Tilt and Bogue, David Bogue, 1841-1853, 235305 (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - Checks and sight drafts drawn on or endorsed by George Cruikshank, circa 1830-1870, 235304 (Box 86, Folder 4-5)
      - Worship of Bacchus, accounts, statements and correspondence, circa 1851-1875, 235303 (Box 87, Folder 1-7)
    - Sub-sub-series 4: Sketches and drawings, notes, fragments, printed material, 1819-1878, undated, 235270
      - Bank Restriction Note, [1819], 235301 (Box 87, Folder 8)
      - Bill Sykes and his Bulldog, drawing from Oliver Twist, 1838, 235300 (Box 87, Folder 9)
      - The British Beehive, notes and sketches from A Penny Political Picture for the People, 1867, 235299 (Box 87, Folder 10)
      - Etchings on glass (folders 11-33), circa 1870, 235298
      - Bag of gold and Sedan chair getting upstairs, 235297 (Box 87, Folder 11)
      - Bandy Tom singing "Lord Bateman", 235296 (Box 87, Folder 12)
      - Bandy Tom and Worshipping, 235295 (Box 87)
      - Boy carrying a large book, from a drawing by W. Thackeray, 235294 (Box 87, Folder 14)
      - Boy smoking and Drury Lane, 235293 (Box 87, Folder 15)